ASHISH PRAKASH NAIR

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Singapore | +65-93768422 | ashish.prakash.nair@gmail.com | thttps://sq.linkedin.com/in/ashishnair57

Summary

Senior Software Developer with 7+ years of experience in the field of the software development lifecycle. Working knowledge of Agile methodologies to accomplish project milestones according to specific timeframes. Possess a BS in Information Technology.

Education

- Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, University of Mumbai.
- Diploma of Computer Technology, Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education.

Certifications

Certified Blockchain Developer, Simplifearn, Sep 2021

Skills

Languages: PHP, Javascript, Python.

Node.js (Express.js and lookback.io), PHP (Core + framework like Codeigniter and Technologies:

Symfony), ReactJS, Vue.js, MySql, Postgresql, MongoDB, Rest Api, WebSockets, AWS,

Bash, Git, Docker, Kubernetes.

OS: Linux (Ubuntu)

Professional Experience

Full Stack Developer - Comtech Team Zilliga Research Pte. Ltd.

Singapore April 2021 - Present

Blockchain platform company for hosting decentralized applications

- Build decentralized applications (DApps) for buying and selling Non Fungible Tokens(NFTs) for the company.
 - Led design and development of data models in Node.js to create a minimum viable product.
 - Designed and implemented algorithm to solve customer's requirement for reselling the brought NFT's on Zilliga's Marketplace resulting in the company's revenue by 11%.
- Led the development of the Auto Kyc module requested by 60% of the customers.
 - o Built auto kyc module using Ares and Artemis a product of Cynopsis.co.
- Build a media upload service for uploading media sure as product images and video.
 - o Built image upload on AWS S3 and Video upload on Vimeo.
- Build notification services to send notification across registration, purchase and kyc process.
 - Built notification service using AWS SES service.
 - Dynamic content creation for sending mail using Handlebar.js, HTML and CSS.
 - Resulted in 100% satisfaction by all Zilliqa customers.

Backend Developer - Tech Team

Equatorial Marine Fuel Management Pte Ltd.

April 2019 - May 2021

Singapore

Bunkering company for fuel delivery to different type of Vessels (Ships)

- Build ERP portal for automating the whole operational process from placing an order, scheduling a delivery, inventory management and barge management, this in turn increased the efficiency by 80%.
 - Led design and development of microservice architecture comprising order entry, management, conversation, revenue reporting and delivery workflow tracking in Symfony php, Node.js and MySql.
- Build a Scoring Algorithm to score all generated schedules by operation team and select a specific schedule based on the highest score, this improved the efficiency of fuel delivery operation which in turn increase the revenue of company by 20%
- Successfully setup Digitalocean linux server, virtualized environment using docker and Gitlab CI pipeline.
- Build a customized reporting system for operational process and revenue generated.
- Introduced Agile methodologies for better Superior quality product and Customer satisfaction.
- Implemented WebSockets for real time data update across the application.
- Led juniors engineers, did code reviewing and managed the deployment cycle on cloud.

Achievement:

My team's name was published in Manifold Times (Online new portal) in Asia for the SmartBunker Application.

Senior Software Engineer - Technical Dept Team Clockworks Business Solutions Pvt Ltd.

India

August 2018 - March 2019

Services based and consulting company

Client B2X - German Cloud-based repair management software company

- Designed, developed and tested an assortment of improvements to in-house systems with React.js, Node.js and Mysql so that both performance and functionality were enhanced.
- Analyzed existing programs in order to discover inefficiencies, bugs and bottlenecks that were then fixed and rewritten.
- Code reviewing and providing assistance to junior developers.

Senior Software Engineer - Tech Team

India

Sanghvi Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (Product MyGlamm)

April 2017 to August 2018

Ecommerce company for selling beauty products

- Designed and developed Rest Api's for Create product, Manage inventory and manage dynamic pages content from portal.
- Designed and developed algorithm to solve all company's requirements for Multi-Level marketing (MLM) strategies.
- Implemented add to cart and checkout flow including payment gateway integration.

Software Developer - Tech Team Shotformats Digital Works Pvt. Ltd.

India

May 2016 to March 2017

VAS and Media production company

- Build many WAP websites using youtube Api's for the company.
- Designed and developed an insurance portal for managing mobile insurance and antivirus products.
- Done Requirement gathering for the business team, created technical documents and explained the same to the team.
- Led juniors engineers, did code reviewing and managed the deployment cycle on cloud.

Software Engineer
Tejora Private Limited

India

Services based and consulting company

Client Axis Direct - Trading portal of Axis Securities

- Implemented graphs using Highcharts library, jQuery and Rest Api's for visualization of live stock price.
- Implemented ticker window using jQuery and Rest Api's to show live stock price.

Client Tax2Win - Cloud-based CA portal

• Designed and developed a tax e-filing feature which included reading tax payer details from PDF, uploading documents, calculating tentative tax and charging customers for CA fees.

Client Axis Bank - Leading banking in India

- Designed and developed a loan management system for the loan approval process.
 - Led design and development of whole applications in PHP to create a viable product.
 - Built loan filing, document upload, verification of documents, loan approval on different stages and reporting module.
 - Designed and implemented algorithms to solve all employee's requirements for loan approval strategies.
- Designed and developed a cloud-based Electronic Operations Process Manual for the client to guide all its trainee officers with different banking processes.
- Designed and developed a marketplace module in an existing internal social networking application for buying and selling of used products.

Achievement:

 My company won an award for the loan management portal that me and my team made and in turn we received an appreciation mail from the company's CEO and good increment that year.

Languages Known

English * Hindi * Marathi * Malayalam